Kontakt

www.linkedin.com/in/paulwolter (LinkedIn)

Top-Kenntnisse

Start-ups
Public Relations
Social Media

Languages

Deutsch Englisch

Honors-Awards #30u30-Crew 2017

Paul Wolter

public affairs and communications for tech companies
Berlin

Zusammenfassung

I am a communication professional, focused on Public Relations and Public Affairs, with extensive experiences within the tech industry and startups. My activities within the startup-ecosystem, especially for the German Startups Association, allowed me to build up a strong personal network of founders, Venture Capitalists and other players within that ecosystem as well as economic and political journalists. Besides Public Relations, Public Affairs is my major field of activity. For the German Startups Association i am in dialogue with decision-makers in politics and advise on legislation with the aim to establish a VC- and startup-friendly environment in Germany.

Berufserfahrung

Raisin Head Of Communications März 2022 - Present (1 Monat) Berlin, Deutschland

Startup-Verband
Freelance Policy Advisor
Februar 2022 - März 2022 (2 Monate)
Berlin, Deutschland

BOXXPORT.com co-founder & CEO Februar 2021 - Januar 2022 (1 Jahr) Hamburg, Deutschland

BOXXPORT.com is the world's leading B2B marketplace for trading ocean containers. Using real-time data on container availability and price, ocean containers can be traded in 184 countries around the world, no matter where they are located - whether in port, on a construction site or on a company's premises. BOXXPORT creates complete transparency for the first time - for the local trader, via industrial companies, up to globally operating freight forwarders. The global trade with containers thus becomes faster, more

efficient and more convenient. Since going live in July 2019, BOXXPORT has managed to grow steadily and exponentially increase the trade of containers on its B2B marketplace. The Hamburg-based startup was founded by industry experts who have been successfully working in the container industry for decades and therefore knows the immense opportunities, but also the current and upcoming challenges of this market.

Bundesverband Deutsche Startups e.V. 5 Jahre

Director Public Affairs and Communications März 2018 - Januar 2021 (2 Jahre 11 Monate) Berlin und Umgebung, Deutschland

Manager Communications & PR September 2016 - Februar 2018 (1 Jahr 6 Monate) Berlin

Communications & PR
Februar 2016 - August 2016 (7 Monate)
Berlin

The German Startups Association was founded in 2012 and is the representative of startups in Germany. Our unique bottom up approach is reflected in all that we do. Headquartered in Berlin with fourteen regional representations, we are constantly growing. Bringing together more than 600 startups from various sectors and in all stages and over 50 corporate members and business angels to create synergies between old and new economy. It is our aim to advise on legislation, connect founders, startups, and investors to create a broad network within an entrepreneurial friendly environment. By fostering these relationships, the German Startups Association builds bridges between global startup hubs, nations and continents. We undertake research both on a national and international level to create much needed evidence for the importance of startups and foster active international exchange with startup tours to New York, Tel Aviv and the Silicon Valley.

viafintech Communications/Buiness Development November 2015 - Januar 2016 (3 Monate) Berlin

Communications & PR, Marketing, Business Development

Serviceplan Consulting Group

Communications & PR Februar 2015 - April 2015 (3 Monate) Berlin

The Serviceplan Group is the largest owner and partner-managed agency group in Europe. In the Houses of Communication, the only fully integrated agency model in Germany, all manner of communication disciplines work under one roof; whether brand strategists, creative professionals, media, design or online specialists, web designers, dialogue or CRM experts, market researchers, PR consultants, sales or content specialists.

Reed Exhibitions
Editor for the Exhibition and Congress "Moderner Staat"
Dezember 2013 - Dezember 2013 (1 Monat)
Berlin

Deutscher Städte- Und Gemeindebund Communications & PR/Public Affairs; Internship April 2012 - September 2012 (6 Monate) Berlin

Ausbildung

Otto-Friedrich-Universität Bamberg

Master of Science (M.Sc.), European Economic Studies · (2013 - 2016)

Technische Universität Ilmenau
Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Medienwirtschaft · (2009 - 2013)